PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Joshua specializes in IT Management and Governance platforms with a deep knowledge of Agile Scrum, DevOps, IT Service Management (ITSM), Asset Management, IT Operations Management (ITOM) and Configuration Management Database (CMDB) processes and platforms.

His project experiences and personality provide him the exceptional abilities to translate customer goals into practical priorities and to manage customer expectations from ideation through service delivery.

Josh serves as a consultant for a variety of financial, retail, health care and federal, state & local government agencies. Josh has also obtained a Secret clearance and holds CompTIA Security+ certification status.

CERTIFICATIONS AND ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate and Professional
- AWS Certified DevOps Engineer Professional
- BMC Discovery (ADDM) and CMDB
- Certified Scrum Master (ScrumAlliance)
- DevOps tool chains (Atlassian, AWS, GitHub and ServiceNow)
- JavaScript, Python, Perl and Java APIs
- ServiceNow Certified Implementation
 Specialist (Platform, ITSM Professional,
 Discovery, Event Management, Service
 Mapping, Cloud Management)

EDUCATION

University of Iowa, Bachelor of Science, Psychology Universidad de Los Andes, Spanish Minor

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Unisys Corporation, 2011 – Present *Sr Consulting Manager/Architect*

- Provides consulting assessments, platform health checks and roadmaps to help customers obtain increasing levels of value from their IT investments.
- Engages with client technical teams, business stakeholders and global delivery teams to ensure successful IT Management platform deployments using Agile-Scrum methodologies (e.g. Story Creation, Product Backlog Refinement and Sprint Planning).
- Uses Docker container based Python APIs to analyze & migrate clients' legacy platform data to modernize, consolidate and reduce cost of their IT management platforms (e.g. ETL migration of BMC FootPrints, Atlassian JIRA to ServiceNow).
- Creates educational presentation content on CMDB & Cloud Discovery deployment experiences for customer consumption.

Computer Sciences Corp (DXC Technology), 2000 – 2010 *Independent Consultant*

 Designed, developed and implemented many ITSM/ITOM applications in support of Managed Services Provider and Client environments (e.g. JP Morgan, NASA). Delivered integrated workflow applications to support a new business unit acquisition (CSC's eHub Cloud) to include Computer Telephony, Discovery, Event and CMDB integrations with B2B ticket exchange APIs (Perl, Java, Web Services).

Credit Suisse - First Boston, 1999 - 2000 Independent Consultant

- Designed, developed and deployed application enhancement requests using Remedy platform development tools, Perl, and Java SDKs.
- Upgraded On Premise Remedy applications and implemented a resilient data replication designs across regions in North America, Europe and the Pacific Rim.

Telegroup, 1997 – 1999 *Applications Developer & Systems Integrator*

- Designed, developed and implemented a new CRM application to service the sales and retail customers of a global telecommunications provider.
- Delivered a custom Route Change Management application integrated with switch circuit testing/capacity analysis tools to support financial business decision making.

INTERESTS AND ACTIVITIES

Avid world traveler, trekker and aspiring SCUBA diver.